Joshua Taguicana

Web Developer



About

A new web developer dedicated to building creative websites and continue learning in new skills in a work environment. Previously worked in accounting and gained valuable organizational, timemanagement, and communication skills to creatively solve problems both individually and as a team.



Contact

joshtaguicana@gmail.com (647) 929-6216 /in/joshua-taguicana www.joshtag.com



Interests

- Music
- Guitar
- Piano
- Basketball
- Hockey
- Football
- Tennis
- Volleyball
- Snowboarding
- Golf

Work Experience

Teaching Assistant BrainStation

June 2019 - Present

- Assisted educators with the marking of assignments students as well as prep course entrance assignments for prospective students
- Set up and organized student files and folders for the new cohort and updated throughout the course
- Created daily challenges and white-boarding questions for students to assist with learning and understanding of the current weeks topic
- Improve learning experience through mentorship of student, implementing student feedback, and mini code alongs

Fund Accountant CIBC Mellon

April 2018 - March 2019

- Ensured accuracy of a fund's trades, cash transactions, corporate actions, and verified correct pricing securities to properly calculate value of the fund portfolio
- Audited the work performed by other team members for the department to ensure accuracy and compliance with department and client instructions
- Calculated daily income accruals, expenses, interest, and dividend payments and ensured proper postings to the fund portfolio and analyzed daily changes in compliance with client exception tolerances
- Prepared daily and monthly distribution reports for clients as well as reinvestment calculations for distributions

Quality Assurance Agent Money Key

October 2016 - March 2018

- Audited the highest amount of loans firm wide through ensuring compliance with business and state regulatory policies by analysis of pay frequency, pay averages, and leverage resulting in higher quality lending due diligence
- Lead in training programs to assist new employees familiarize themselves with company processes
- Process debits and credits batches to meet the daily deadline. Audit batches for accuracy and confirm with bank
- Generated and analyzed trend reports for sales leads and customer service calls for management and supervisor review, identifying a need for stricter verification policies and customer education

Education

BrainStation Full-Time Web Development Diploma

Ryerson University Bachelor of Commerce – Accounting

Sheridan College Business Administration – Accounting

June 2019

August 2016

April 2013



Projects

Warcraft Auctions - A data visualization project aimed at giving World of Warcraft players information about the auction house to buy and sell and build their gold. Created for my BrainStation capstone.

Star Wars Database - A simple database made to find Star Wars characters, spaceships, and planets. Made to teach myself react hooks and databases.

Webdev Slayr - A turned based fighting game with a web developer theme. Created to teach myself Vue.js and Sketch.